# brian dunnington

http://briandunnington.github.io briandunnington@gmail.com 480.652.7862

#### about me

I am truly a full-stack developer. I have written countless Windows and UWP apps, and am well-versed in all things .NET and the most obscure details of C#, but am just as comfortable writing React web apps or building out Node.js back-ends. I am all-in on cloud development - I have built serverless solutions leveraging AWS Lambdas and Azure Functions and have used Azure Logic apps to create workflows with zero code. I have built solutions that use Azure Media Services to ingest and encode user-generated content and to stream live drone footage in real time. On the more esoteric side, I have written React & Redux style libraries in BrightScript and then implemented them in large-scale Roku apps.

I have a drive to never stop learning, but an even greater drive to share what I have learned with others - to take that knowledge and present it in a way that is easy and fun to understand, giving others the tools and building blocks to make them even more successful. To that end, I have created numerous frameworks, SDKs, libraries, sample code, presentations, and documentation - shared both internally with my teams and publicly on my dev blog and on Github. I have contributed to many open-source projects and worked hard to build a community around my own open source project. Although I continue to love solving software problems, I am gaining more and more satisfaction out of the personal side of software development – documenting, demoing, and interacting with the people and communities that make software development so great.

# work history

#### **Ratio Interactive/Globant**

#### Living Room Practice Lead, 2008-Present

Ratio builds apps and websites for large clients such as AT&T, Sony, Microsoft, Disney, HBO, and many others. Beginning as an independent contractor, to Senior Software Developer, to leading the entire Living Room team, I have been able to work in a variety of technologies and architect large-scale solutions, as well as lead diverse teams and focus on advocating for people.

- Been a proponent for open-sourcing our libraries to the larger community
- Presented at numerous brown-bag sessions and official company Lunch and Learn events
- Specific focus on speaking, writing, and communicating clearly with technical and non-technical folks at all levels
- Disney Star Wars Force Awakens & Rogue One Xbox apps Built using React + WinJS with a custom JSX-transpileon-build tool. Back-end was built with a custom Node.js API hosted in an Azure Web App utilizing Azure Media Services to encode and stream HLS videos; Azure Storage used to host all other app assets
- Crunchyroll Windows/Windows Phone UWP app Worked with Microsoft on pre-release Windows 10/SDK bits.
   App included full Cortana integration for browsing, playback, and search. Created and open-sourced a custom mocking framework for use in unit tests that dynamically created mock classes from discovered interfaces
- Augustine Web app React + Redux front-end with a custom Node.js back-end using a Redis cache and Mongo DB for storage
- HBO GO & NOW Roku apps Rebuilt from the ground up on Roku's latest SceneGraph SDK. Created and open-sourced React + Redux implementations in BrightScript

#### **Growl for Windows – OSS Project**

creator/lead developer, 2008 - 2016 - http://www.growlforwindows.com

Created and maintain the Growl for Windows project, a notification system inspired by the original Growl for OSX. Growl for Windows provides users with a consistent and highly-configurable way to receive unobtrusive notifications from other applications and websites.

- Built a community through developer support; over 50 applications now support Growl notifications on Windows
- Administer and monitor Google Groups discussion list for the project; often praised for speed of response, helpfulness, and commitment to end users and developers alike
- Helped develop and standardize the GNTP protocol spec; provides a unified way to send and receive notifications in a cross-platform manner
- Robust extensibility system for creating custom displays, forwarders, and subscription modules
- Created several developer SDKs, including C#/.NET, JavaScript, and Flash, and supported other developers who
  created libraries for Java, Perl, Python, PHP, SQL, Ruby, C++, and more
- Contributed to numerous other OSS projects to extend their capability by adding Growl support

#### element code project

#### developer/co-owner, 2006-2016

element code project is a small development shop that focuses on building web apps and tools for a variety of clients.

- Ran all technical aspects of the business including: sales support, estimation, project management, software development, documentation, and operations
- Worked with a wide range of technologies to solve client challenges
- World Health Web app built using ASP.NET/C#, JavaScript, and SQL. Provides a webservice endpoint for backoffice processes to push updated member information
- Core Performance Prescribes customized workout programs and meal plans based on individual factors, which
  can also be delivered via personalized video podcast. Exposes a JSON-based webservice API for third-party
  integration
- US Airways Used creative thinking to leverage the 30+ year-old legacy system for use in modern-day applications.
   Built a queue processing system that replaced the need for several agents to constantly monitor and manually process work items while reducing costly back-end transactions

## **America West Airlines/US Airways**

# **Enterprise Architect, 2002-2005**

I was part of a very small team of Enterprise Architects that designed and developed a company-wide Enterprise Framework that was the basis for many consumer-facing and internal business tools. The Enterprise Framework handled everything from talking to back-end databases, interfacing with the legacy reservations system, abstracting all of the various business entities and models, as well as the main business logic and workflows for critical areas such as reservations, member account management, flight and operations tracking, and web check -in.

- Focus on communication with all levels of the company from C-level executives to development teams
- Created developer support artifacts for all aspects of the enterprise framework, including SDKs, API references, and integration guides
- Created and developed the company's DirectConnect product an XML webservice based on the Open Travel
  Alliance (OTA) standards that was used by other airline and travel industry companies to integrate with the US
  Airways systems
- Shaped the architecture of the new AmericaWest.com website, which was rewritten from scratch in C#/.NET (previously based on ASP/VB/COM). Also developed logging and exception handling subsystems, as well as several data-access components for sources such as SQL, Oracle, DB2, and the SHARES reservation system
- Designed and developed the SHARES Gateway a scalable socket server with smart connection pooling that can
  be scaled up with additional instances on the same machine or across distributed machines with automatic load
  balancing. The gateway is the backbone of the public-facing USAirways.com website as well as many other public
  and internal tools, processing millions of transactions and responsible for millions of dollars of revenue per day

## education

#### **Bachelor of Arts in Business Administration**

Washington State University – 1998